Artyom Orlov

Senior Frontend Developer & Team Lead

Visa sponsorship required

iart2.o@outlook.com +7 91 9320-1005 <u>LinkedIn</u>

T-shaped, responsible, and collaborative Software Engineer and Team Lead. 8+ years of experience of development in startups, consultancies, and product companies. Advanced skills in frontend development, an expert in JavaScript, various frontend frameworks, and libraries. Comprehensive knowledge of Java and backend utilities. Passionate about user experience and clear software architecture. Fond of teamwork and productive meetings.

Technical Skills

Languages TypeScript, JavaScript, Java, Golang

Frameworks & libs ReactJS, Svelte, Effector, Recoil, Redux, Apollo GraphQL, TreeJS, OSM, ExpressJS, Spring

Professional Experience_

Remedy Inc

Senior Frontend Engineer & Team Lead

Dec 2019 - present

Developed a flexible platform to allow customers to choose a clinic and get or order some medical services online

- Migrated a complex legacy project from JavaScript/AngularJS to TypeScript/React with unit and integrating testing
- Significantly increased accessibility for users with mobile devices
- Developed and implemented UI-library with Unit tests and documentation based on Storybook
- Designed frontend architecture
- Leading and influencing software engineering best practices within teams for the full software development life cycle, including documentation, design, coding standards, code reviews, building, testing, deployment, and other operations.
- Led a team of 5 members

Vinavis

Senior Software Engineer Nov 2018 - Dec 2019

Developed a high-loaded management system for unmanned vehicles

- Architected and developed a scalable real-time ReactJS application
- Improved performance from 10 to 60 FPS for the most loaded parts of the app
- Implemented CI/CD for the frontend part of the application
- Developed and Implemented multi-domain OAuth-based authentication
- Developed and Implemented JS library for on-map data visualization
- Coordinated teamwork of 3 developers

ITeco

Software Engineer & Senior Software Engineer

Apr 2016 - Nov 2018

Developed and successfully delivered SPA (part of a complex enterprise solution) for letting clients book deposit boxes online for one of the biggest banks in Russia

- Developed and implemented a module for remote printing
- Created about 20 new components for internal UI library
- · Achieved 90+% test coverage on the Backend side
- Implemented integration with other banking modules and flows
- Made several major CI/CD improvements which allowed to reduce deployment time from 17 to 3 minutes
- Interviewed 30 candidates, mentored 4 junior engineers

Freelance & Web Studios (SEMark, Consulting plus)

Web developer & Lead Web Developer

Sep 2012 - Feb 2016

- Developed various company projects as a full-stack JavaScript/PHP & Python developer
- Led development of Web and Mobile application
- Developed and delivered a solution for municipalities to allow local governments to handle incoming citizen's application
- Processed incoming business requirement
- Delivering innovative technical solutions to improve business outcomes
- Implemented integration with third-party APIs

Education

Master of Computer Science

State Technical University, 2016